<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>I Write Stuff</title>
    <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com" />
    <updated>2025-06-06T13:14:35-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>elmikewalsh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How To Choose An Email Service Without Going Insane</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/how-to-choose-an-email-service-without-going-insane/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/how-to-choose-an-email-service-without-going-insane/</id>
            <category term="Tech"/>

        <updated>2025-05-21T19:47:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p1">It’s official - I have spent waaaaay more time (more time than a sane person would admit) investigating the best email platform for me at this moment. I am on a roll deGoogling, and have been for well over a year. Gmail was one of the first ones out. However, this left me in search of an email service I could be comfortable with. I have passed through, tested, used and left the following services (in no particular order that I can remember):</p>
<div class="post__toc">
<h3>Email Providers Unnecessarily Tested</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk57">Postale.io</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk58">Proton</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk59">Tuta</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5a">Infomaniak</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5b">Purelymail</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5c">MXRoute</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5d">Fastmail</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5e">iCloud Mail</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5f">Fastmail</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="p1">I have downloaded probably every email program (Canary, Spark, em, Edison, etc) from the App Store, and removed them.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/email-services-a-rant/">I previously commented on some email services</a>; some opinions have changed. I still do not feel quite comfortable with my current service (returned to Proton). Here’s an update on what I previously commented, in the hopes that writing it out may help me actually come to some sort of definitive conclusion:</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk57" class="p1">Postale.io</h3>
<p class="p1">This is the first service I used for my very own domain name email, leaving Gmail behind. Nothing but good things to say. Great price for basic email needs &amp; unlimited custom domains. I left mainly because I wanted more options and ideally a beautiful and free native mail app, which they don’t provide. They redesigned their website and admin portal recently but still use the ugly-as-sin Roundcube webmail. As my email solution needs to cater to family members of different tech levels, intuitive and “pretty” are important.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk58" class="p3">Proton</h3>
<p class="p1">Had Visionary, loved it, left because of the price. Later returned; still love the service. The more I have looked into email security the more I come to realize (like many) that:</p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li1">Email is not secure by nature.</li>
<li class="li1">Encrypted email loses some of its power the moment I send an email to a less-secure service (like Google). Everything I send (and receive) from a Gmail address, for example, can be accessed through the other person’s email. This article says it all: Google Has Most of My Email Because It Has All of Yours ( <a href="https://mako.cc/copyrighteous/google-has-most-of-my-email-because-it-has-all-of-yours" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">https://mako.cc/copyrighteous/google-has-most-of-my-email-because-it-has-all-of-yours</a> ).</li>
</ol>
<p class="p1">So the big question is - if encrypted email is only encrypted if you communicate with other encrypted addresses only, is the high price of encrypted email services worth it (at present). Like the company, love the product. Not a fan of the pricing, but mostly because we don't need most of the services. An option for multiple domain evade email plans (like Tuta) would be great, but not going to unlimited just to use 3 domain names. The Family plan is almost perfect but 6 users, yes. Only 3 domains.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Really?<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>6 domains on Family plan at that pricing and I think it’s correct.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk59" class="p1">Tuta</h3>
<p class="p1">I like Tuta’s approach to developing their apps and system on Linux, so all systems get the apps at the same time. The security story they’re selling is also great. Pricing is also better than Proton, if you’re just looking for email (and calendar).<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>The app is not ugly. It is very minimalist though.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I am not personally a fan that, when you change paid plans, they automatically bill you for the new plan, and then “refund” you for the old one. Reddit is full of people confused about this; take a look there if that is a concern.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5a" class="p1">Infomaniak</h3>
<p class="p1">Ok, so you will go to their site, see what they offer, see their prices, and you will be very interested. As I was. I circled back around on this one many times, mostly because of the price. And there’s a LOT of information. Then, once the info was read, I had questions, so I emailed support. This is where it gets ugly. Two main pain points here:</p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li1">I would on average wait 10 days to receive a reply</li>
<li class="li1">The reply I received would not address and answer completely the questions, which were clearly expressed.</li>
</ol>
<p class="p1">They have a very strange setup where, if you want to use multiple domains for email addresses, one domain is the “main” one, and the other domains are simply “aliases”. This is super annoying when trying to set up different emails on different domains for different users. Of all the companies listed here, it is the ONLY one using this odd setup, and they can’t seem to explain it well. It’s not a “European thing” either, as many other companies there are able to explain their product well.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5b" class="p3">Purelymail</h3>
<p class="p1">Great setup, easy, really reasonable pricing ($10/year) for unlimited space, domains, email accounts. Backend is ugly as sin, and if you are not proficient in setting up DNS records, this is not for you. You’ll also need an email app, if that’s a concern for you.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5c" class="p3">MXRoute</h3>
<p class="p1">I hopped onboard this one for about a year, due to its low price. They offer an email app that is even customizable. But it’s based on Google’s Material Design, so if you are in Apple’s world (as I am) and like how Apple designs apps (which I generally do) then this app will be yuck.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5d" class="p3">Fastmail</h3>
<p class="p1">Fastmail offered a Family plan, which was a reasonable price. Setup was nice and quick. I can't really think of much to say. I did not like the mobile app because of things like Notes, Calendar, Files, being there, and there is no function to remove them. So I moved on.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5e" class="p3">iCloud Mail</h3>
<p class="p1">I really wanted to like this one. I really do. Multiple domain emails are possible, but just can’t get behind the idea that all your email addresses are really just an alias for the iCloud email address.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1irsu6lfk5f" class="p3">Fastmail</h3>
<p class="p1">Ok, so during this entire investigation, I circled back to check on Fastmail a couple of times. In all of this, they did not have the cheapest nor most expensive service. Price was reasonable. Once I came to the conclusion that completely encrypted zero-knowledge email was not a need I had I checked back in with them. Right around this time Fastmail made a (controversial if you are on Reddit) redesign to their inbox. But in this update, they added an option to add or remove the services you want to display at the bottom of their mobile app. As stupid as it sounds, this was a deal-breaker the first time around; hated having 6 big ol icons at the bottom of the app, for 4 services I didn’t want to use. Now I can just click and hide what I don’t want.</p>
<p class="p1">Finally after an eternity of decision-fatigue, I pulled the trigger and we’re back at Fastmail. It’s all there, easy to set up, and fast as fast can be.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Masked Email / Aliases</strong></p>
<p class="p1">I’ll just briefly add this note: Fastmail provided integration with Bitwarden and 1Password Keychains to create masked email addresses. However, during my second time with Proton, I got into Proton Pass and their way of doing alias emails more. So sticking with this one, but getting the subscription through SimpleLogin (which includes Proton Pass), rather than through Proton Pass (which includes Simple Login).</p>
<p class="p1">But that’s a post for another day (maybe).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Quick Update On The Website</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/publii-cms-website-multilanguage/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/publii-cms-website-multilanguage/</id>
            <category term="Tech"/>
            <category term="Life &amp; Stuff"/>

        <updated>2025-05-10T14:17:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It's been awhile, and it's a completely different world than my last post saw (and will likely be a different world tomorrow as well).</p>
<p>I've got some notes here and there which will eventually become posts / articles / rants on this website. For now, I was able to grab a few minutes here and there to update one part of this site which was bothering me - the language selector.</p>
<p>For as much as I love it, <a href="https://getpublii.com" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">Publii CMS</a> (which I highly recommend) still has no multilanguage option available. Currently I deploy two different versions of my site in two languages, to two different domains. Due to the time involved in setting up links between articles and pages, I simply had an English / Spanish link which would take you to the homepage of the site in the other language.</p>
<p><strong>But no longer!</strong></p>
<p>Now, clicking on English / Spanish will take you to that same page in the other language. In the case of the blog, there are a few older articles that exist currently in only one language. For articles that don't exist in the other language, you will be taken to the main blog page of the other language, rather than the homepage.</p>
<p>Hopefully this keeps you all on the site a bit longer to poke around and read stuff.</p>
<p>Hope to write more soon, about this, that, and the other. Until next time!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Your Email - It’s Not &quot;Swiss Safe&quot;</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/your-email-its-not-swiss-safe/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/your-email-its-not-swiss-safe/</id>
            <category term="Tech"/>

        <updated>2025-01-31T19:56:14-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3>If It's Swiss, It's Secure - Swiss Cheese has holes In It, and so does this idea.</h3>
<p>I’ve recently had the pleasure (torture) of studying in-depth many, many, many free and paid email solutions, looking for the perfect solution for family, personal and work. As a bit of context, after waking up the need to leave Google for privacy concerns (my phone does not have a single Google application - yay!).<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I went first to <a href="https://proton.me/" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">Proton</a> and stayed there for about a year, as a Visionary client (when I go in, it’s all in).</p>
<p class="p1">In the end, I can’t say that Proton was bad, just way more than I needed, and way more expensive than I wanted. Though I will note that exporting out of Proton, and the subsequent attempt to downgrade my account to Unlimited from Visionary, rather than canceling, was quite evil.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">(when making high-tier customers press CANCEL, btw, don’t secretly downgrade me to a lesser plan and charge me. I will expose you here for the dozens of bots and half-dozen people who visit to see)</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">Anyways, in my search for the “perfect” email company for me, I came across a number of companies that pushed the idea that “our servers are in XYZ country (usually Switzerland) and so your data is completely safe. Laws here protect your privacy. (In one famous and extreme case, your data is stored in underground bunkers impervious to nuclear attacks. Good to know in the case all life on the planet is screwed, my email is safe).</p>
<p class="p1">Here’s the thing about the above argument (not the bunker) - your data is only safe if the laws protecting them in that country never change. Ever.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>In the case the government changes, or new laws are passed, or your country is invaded, your laws and Swiss protection don’t mean anything at all.</p>
<p class="p1">So, not really sure why you would push that as a sales point.</p>
<p class="p1">Maybe you are relying on the tradition argument - <em>“Our country has never….”</em><span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>or <em>“We would never….”</em></p>
<p class="p1">I’m not saying that the services that promote this are bad email companies. Far from it; most of them are pretty good.</p>
<p class="p1">For those who are attracted by the privacy laws argument, just turn on the toxic world news and count how many countries and governments are now doing things that haven’t been done before. Things that they would “never do”.</p>
<p class="p1">And I’m thinking about the democratically run countries.</p>
<p class="p1">My point (if any)?</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Your information is not secure or private just because it is in a specific country or region. Privacy and security has much more to do with encryption than location.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bariloche: From Top to Bottom</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/bariloche-from-top-to-bottom/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/bariloche-from-top-to-bottom/</id>
            <category term="Photos"/>

        <updated>2025-01-25T13:46:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Took a family trip in November 2024 over the mountains to Bariloche, Argentina. Sharing some photos from the top of Otto Hill, as well as a few other locations. November is a great time to go (for weather and lack of tourists)</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2465.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2465-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2480.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2480-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2481.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2481-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2486.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2486-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2487.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2487-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2490.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2490-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2491.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2491-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2501.webp" data-size="1613x907"><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/73/gallery/IMG_2501-thumbnail.webp" alt="" width="720" height="405"></a></figure>
</div></div>
<p class="align-center"><em>Bariloche, Argentina.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Fuck You, Microsoft</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/fuck-you-microsoft/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/fuck-you-microsoft/</id>
            <category term="Tech"/>

        <updated>2025-01-19T17:49:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p1">I’m sure many people have said that before. I’m not one to rail against companies for being large, faceless, cold, and motivated only by money.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>I used Microsoft products and worked on Windows for over 30 years. I can’t really say I have a personal feeling about them one way or the other.</p>
<p class="p1">However, they recently decided to increase their Microsoft 365 prices, for Basic and Family plans. Ok, that in itself is nothing new, as companies do that from time to time, maybe even for reasonable excuses.</p>
<p class="p1">But the way in which it is being implemented is terrible and shows no consideration for the consumer.</p>
<p class="p1">This <a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/computing/microsoft-365-gets-massive-45-percent-price-hike-and-its-all-to-do-with-ai-tools" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">article from Tom’s Guide</a> provides the scoop. I take exception to (many things people say/write), but particularly the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">“Microsoft will increase the prices of Microsoft 365 Personal and Family in the U.S. by $3 per month or $30 for annual subscriptions. It's the first price hike since 365 launched, <strong>but the good news is users don't have to opt-in for the AI upgrade.</strong>”</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">Read that again: “<strong>But the good news is users don't have to opt-in for the AI upgrade.</strong>” Ok, so the good news is that a half-baked AI implementation that no one wants is being forced upon me, and I do not have to take any action to pay more for it.</p>
<p class="p1">If I would rather NOT have this “feature”, then I have to jump through hoops to NOT have it. What great news! Work to not get charged for crap.</p>
<p class="p1">I used to not care one way or the other, but now….</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Fuck you, Microsoft.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Email Services: A Rant</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/email-services-a-rant/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/email-services-a-rant/</id>
            <category term="Tech"/>

        <updated>2025-01-10T20:26:59-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="post__toc">
<h3>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1ih991dk93u">Proton</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1ih991dk93v">Fastmail</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1ih991dk940">Purelymail</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1ih991dk941">MXRoute</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1ih991dk942">iCloud Mail</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>I imagine most people just fire up their trusty Gmail account, check and send mail, and call it a day.  But when you think about changing to a service that doesn't openly read and spy on your email, it begins to turn into a lot of work.</p>
<p>My head is to the point it might actually explode. I could go into a lot of detail about each service I encountered, tried and discarded. I'm happy to say that the crusade is coming to an end. On that note, I wanted to share a bit of my findings, in the hopes that it might help other people who are looking for a good, reliable service.</p>
<p><strong>Quick Context:</strong> I am not looking for a high threat-model, military-grade encrypted email. I am looking for a service that will offer general encryption from a company that won't spy on me, or charge me a fortune. Here's what I have found, and my opinions:</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ih991dk93u">Proton</h3>
<p>Had this email set up for family. Actually, I can only say good things about the service offered. The problem? Once it was decided that the offering was more than we were willing to pay, the migration began - as well as the problems:</p>
<ul>
<li>As an organization, I could export all member email except for my own. It turns out it threw up an unknown error, and support finally said it was a really rare issue that was unlikely to be fixed. So instead of receiving an easy-to-use MBOX output, I had to export EML files and import them into the next service. </li>
<li>Once we canceled our plan (Visionary, no less) they confirmed cancellation, but secretly downgraded us to an Unlimited plan. Was not expecting to be charged again, and had to go in and cancel a second time. That is terrible service.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ih991dk93v">Fastmail</h3>
<p>Fastmail offered a Family plan, which was a reasonable price. Setup was nice and quick. I can't really think of much to say. I did not like the mobile app because of things like Notes, Calendar, Files, being there, and there is no function to remove them. Fastmail was "meh" - can't really say I enjoy them, or not. Might be for you. Not for me.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ih991dk940">Purelymail</h3>
<p>Great setup, easy, really reasonable pricing ($10/year) for unlimited space, domains, email accounts. Backend is ugly as sin, and if you are not proficient in setting up DNS records, this is not for you.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ih991dk941">MXRoute</h3>
<p>Checking this one out, this may be what I am looking for. I'll update this once I learn more.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ih991dk942">iCloud Mail</h3>
<p>I really want to like this one. I really do. I will go into detail why I can't later. For me, it has to do with multiple domain emails and really wanting a separate inbox for each one.</p>
<hr>
<p>Ok that's my rant for now. Thanks, hope it's of help, and will update as time permits.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Picture Is Worth 1000 Words</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/a-picture-is-worth-1000-words/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/a-picture-is-worth-1000-words/</id>
            <category term="Life &amp; Stuff"/>

        <updated>2025-01-03T21:09:46-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p3">Manu made a good point the other day in his article about <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/on-featured-images-in-blog-posts" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">adding unnecessary images to articles</a> just to have a photo.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>They say a photo is worth 1,000 words. This year, I will take a shot at typing the 1,000 words, and use photos when necessary.</p>
<p class="p3">So no banner images on posts just to have one (but I will also try to take - and share - more photos in 2025)</p>
<p class="p3">Sorry! :)</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>More Typing, Less Thinking</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/more-typing-less-thinking/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/more-typing-less-thinking/</id>
            <category term="Life &amp; Stuff"/>

        <updated>2024-12-31T14:10:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="p3">So, in some contexts, the phrase “measure twice, cut once” makes sense.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>But sometimes one can think so much that you fail to do anything at all.</p>
<p class="p3">So this year, I hope to let loose and write more, think less. (Oh crap).<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>:)</p>
<p class="p3">Just have the fingers dance across the keyboard and let it all run out.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>It’s summer in the southern hemisphere, which means it’s hot. And I do not like the heat.</p>
<p class="p3">Seasons are great - if you are bored with one weather pattern, just give it a bit of time and it will change.</p>
<p class="p3">It’s wonderful to feel the breeze and hard-core cold wind in your face in the winter.</p>
<p class="p3">And juuuuust when you’re bored to death with heating the house, spring and summer come around.</p>
<p class="p3">Still, summer heat sucks: after all, in the winter, you can always put on one more layer of clothes.</p>
<p class="p3">But in the summer heat, once it’s all off, there’s nowhere left to go.</p>
<p class="p3">Cheers to you, summer. Now let’s get a move on.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>14 Days In No-Internet Hell</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/14-days-in-no-internet-hell/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/14-days-in-no-internet-hell/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/68/no-internet-hell-2.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tech"/>
            <category term="Humor"/>

        <updated>2024-10-22T09:35:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/68/no-internet-hell-2.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="post-apocalyptic view of city" /></p>
                <div class="post__toc">
<h3>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iav8n6uha">The “Good Old” 4G Days</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iav8n6uib">Talking With Myself - Or Not (Who Are These People?)</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iav91b9bs">14 Days at the End of the World</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iav8n6uic">A Dear Friend Returns</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="p3"><strong>Remembering the good old days when 4G was the latest “high-speed internet” and websites were designed to load quickly.</strong></p>
<p class="p3">There I was, in the heart of South Central Chile, end of August, living a simple, common life of internet addiction - until the storms hit. First, the power flickered out. Then, the internet followed suit, leaving me in a dark, disconnected void.</p>
<p>Boom.</p>
<p>Welcome to No-Internet Hell, where you’re left remembering the good ol’ days of 4G when it felt like the future was at your fingertips, hoping that a drop of that will magically trickle down to you. Well, at least when we weren’t stuck on 3G... </p>
<p class="p3">Two weeks without a connection. And when there was a connection, it was - gasp - 3G. (Not 3 gbps fiber optic. I’m talking about the “mobile” 3G). Before the almighty internet returned to bless us with its presence, I had a lot of time to reflect—mostly on how much I missed reading <a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/your-internet-speed-and-that-of-your-websites-visitor-probably-sucks/">articles about terrible internet speeds</a>. Who knew those words would become my life?</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iav8n6uha" class="p3">The “Good Old” 4G Days</h3>
<p class="p3">Remember when 4G was the best thing since sliced bread? We all thought it was the beginning of a new era. But here’s the kicker: most of the time, you were stuck on 3G because 4G coverage was spotty at best. Back then, even 3G felt like a miracle compared to the dreaded 0G, where your phone became an expensive paperweight. But when 4G actually worked, oh, how fast it was. Websites loaded before you could blink (we didn’t blink much, back in my day). It was quick enough that you didn’t have time to think about how much they sucked (now we just don’t think; that’s what AI is for!).</p>
<p class="p3">Of course, that was back when websites weren’t bogged down with gigabytes of data-hogging nonsense. Remembering this fine piece of literature, <a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/your-internet-speed-and-that-of-your-websites-visitor-probably-sucks/">Your Internet Speed and That of Your Website’s Visitor Probably Sucks</a>, we’ve made things worse by designing websites that only load quickly if you’ve got NASA-level bandwidth. These days, if you’re stuck on 4G - or heaven forbid, 3G - you might as well go make a sandwich while the page loads. And watch the paint on the walls dry. Wherever it needs drying.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iav8n6uib" class="p3">Talking With Myself - Or Not (Who Are These People?)</h3>
<p class="p3">After a few days without the internet, I did what any sane person would do: restarted the router. When that didn’t work (shocking, I know), I moved on to the next best thing—restarting it again. Maybe it would come back! (It didn’t.) So, left with no other option, I actually talked to the people around me. I know, terrifying. It’s not that I dislike conversation, but after so long with the internet, I completely forgot why those other people shared the same space that I did. :)</p>
<p class="p3">I also discovered something fascinating: card games and board games still exist. Yes, those relics from a pre-digital age. They’re not as fun as YouTube or Instagram, but at least no one has to worry about buffering. After a few rounds of <em>carioca</em>, I was ready to crawl back to the 4G days, even if it meant living with the constant cycle of switching to 3G mid-download.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iav91b9bs" class="p3">14 Days at the End of the World</h3>
<p class="p3">Productivity without the internet? It’s a joke. Sure, at first you think, “I’ll finally get some offline work done.” Spoiler: no, you won’t. You’ll realize how deeply you depend on Google for even the most basic tasks, like remembering how long it takes to cook rice. Remember the pre-historic days when we went to the bathroom with a book, and not a phone? (a phone doesn't serve the same dual-purpose that a good ol' paper book can in an emergency)</p>
<p class="p3">Even trying to remember what life was like before we were all glued to the life line that is WiFi feels like a stretch. And yet, ironically, my article on <a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/your-internet-speed-and-that-of-your-websites-visitor-probably-sucks/">why internet speeds suck</a> kept bouncing around my head. Turns out I had firsthand experience now of how bad a slow (or non-existent) connection really is.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iav8n6uic" class="p3">A Dear Friend Returns</h3>
<p class="p3">After an eternity (or so it seemed), the internet came back. My router lit up like a Christmas tree, and I was back online. But the victory was bittersweet. There’s no immediate rush to watch all the Netflix I missed or <a href="https://medium.com/@elmikewalsh/list/in-english-baf770234cb3" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">binge-read Medium articles</a>. Instead, I started reflecting on how we got here—how we built a digital world so bloated with content that even 4G can feel sluggish now (or, at least, that’s what I would like you to think. In reality, it was a frantic rush to make 2 weeks of backlogged projects go away).</p>
<p class="p3">It’s funny, isn’t it? We used to get by with simpler, faster websites. Now we need insane speeds just to keep up with the junk we’ve crammed into them. So if you’re out there still dealing with terrible load times and sluggish sites, I feel for ya. But don’t worry - you’re not missing anything other than crap being pushed and loaded faster and faster.</p>
<p class="p3"><strong>Photo Used:</strong> <a href="https://pixabay.com/photos/city-disaster-end-of-the-world-fire-2444516/" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">pixabay.com</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Become a Millionaire on Medium (How I Made $0.04 In One Month!)</title>
        <author>
            <name>elmikewalsh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/becom-a-millionaire-on-medium-how-i-made-004-in-one-month/"/>
        <id>https://www.elmikewalsh.com/becom-a-millionaire-on-medium-how-i-made-004-in-one-month/</id>
        <media:content url="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/how-i-made-004.webp" medium="image" />
            <category term="Humor"/>

        <updated>2024-10-16T09:30:00-03:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/how-i-made-004.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Image of tiny tree growing out of pennies." /></p>
                <div class="post__toc">
<h3>Table of Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5m">Ignorance Writes Itself</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5n">Find Your Truly Unique Nobody-Is-Doing-This Niche</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5o">Neurotic Stat Tracking</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5p">Show Me The Money!</a></li>
<li><a href="#mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5q">The Lessons Learned</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="p1">Ah, Medium. The land of dreams, where writers come to share their deepest thoughts and worst takes on minimalism. Some are here for community, others for the joy of writing, but most of us came for one thing: cash. Via that glorious <a href="https://medium.com/partner-program" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">Medium Partner Program</a> (MPP) money, which we were told would be flowing our way just for sharing our brilliant ideas. The digital gold rush.</p>
<p class="p1">I’m here to tell you how I turned that dream into reality. I’ve done it. I made $0.04 in one month on Medium. You’re probably asking yourself, “How can I achieve this level of success?” Don’t worry. I’ve got you covered.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5m" class="p1">Ignorance Writes Itself</h3>
<p class="p1">Everyone knows that expertise is overrated. On Medium, it’s all about pretending to know stuff. The key is confidence. The trick is to sprinkle in buzzwords like “mindfulness,” “side hustle,” and “growth mindset.” If you really want to maximize earnings, toss in some crypto talk, even if your only knowledge of cryptocurrency is that it's not a physical coin.</p>
<p class="p1">After initially resisting, on the principle that hard work and effort pay off, I switched to this method, convinced that my in-depth “advice” on how to maximize your website development by following my convoluted <a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/wordpress-2024-static-website-generator/">15-step process to output your WordPress website as a static site</a>. Spoiler: it didn’t.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5n" class="p1">Find Your Truly Unique Nobody-Is-Doing-This Niche</h3>
<p class="p1">I thought I’d stand out by finding the perfect niche. After all, Medium’s full of articles on digital nomads, minimalism and making one digital product and selling 325 variations for $50k a month, so I decided to niche down to something <i>truly unique</i>. I wrote about <a href="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/the-art-of-a-good-password/">how to create a good password</a>. A masterpiece. Naturally, I expected the algorithm to throw my post to the top of the platform.</p>
<p class="p1">What I discovered is that Medium loves niches... if your niche happens to be crypto, minimalism, or tech startups. A heartfelt in-depth guide on how to make a good password? Not so much.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5o" class="p1">Neurotic Stat Tracking</h3>
<p class="p1">This is the real joy of Medium. It’s like checking your social media for likes—on steroids. The moment you hit “publish,” you’ll find yourself obsessively refreshing the stats page. At first, you’ll be optimistic. You’ll picture the hundreds of views piling up, the comments flooding in, the claps accumulating. But instead, you’ll see numbers that look more like the cost of a pack of gum.</p>
<p class="p1">After a week of watching my stats like a hawk, my first milestone arrived. A whopping <strong>two</strong> cents. At that point, I began calculating how long it would take me to buy an actual cup of coffee with my Medium earnings. (It’s a very long time.)</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5p" class="p1">Show Me The Money!</h3>
<p class="p1">Then it happened. After weeks of pouring my heart and soul into my content, the moment of truth arrived. I checked my stats one last time for the month and saw it: <strong>$0.04</strong>. I made it. The big leagues.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img  src="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/earnings-image.jpg" alt="Screenshot of my $0.04 earnings." width="728" height="562" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" srcset="https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-xs.webp 640w ,https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-sm.webp 768w ,https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-md.webp 1024w ,https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-lg.webp 1366w ,https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-xl.webp 1600w ,https://www.elmikewalsh.com/media/posts/67/responsive/earnings-image-2xl.webp 1920w"></figure>
<p class="p1">It was time to celebrate. I poured myself a glass of tap water, sat back, and basked in the glow of my monumental success. Could I afford a yacht? No. Could I afford an iPhone? Nope. But I was officially a paid writer. Technically.</p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1iaq3dh5t5q" class="p1">The Lessons Learned</h3>
<p class="p1">Making money on Medium is, well, possible. Technically. But it’s not about the money (good thing, right?). It’s about the thrill of putting your thoughts into the world and seeing them resonate with, let’s be honest, probably just your mom. That $0.04 is a symbol of potential. The potential to someday—perhaps many, may, may, many years from now—afford a pack of gum.</p>
<p class="p1">So, if you're ready to become a Medium millionaire, remember this: it's not about the payout. It’s about the journey of seeing that stat page inch forward. Someday, with enough perseverance, you might just be able to buy that yacht. Or at least a cup of coffee. Full steam ahead!</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Photo Used:</strong> <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/green-plant-on-brown-round-coins-lZ_4nPFKcV8" target="_blank" class="extlink extlink-icon-1 "  rel="noopener noreferrer">Unsplash.com</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
